# **Benjamin Banwart**

Fort Scott, Kansas

Benjibanwart@gmail.com | (620)404-2094 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio Site

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with experience in full-stack web development including front-end, back-end, database, and testing. Attended a 9 month full-stack software engineering certificate program with Kansas State University. Currently a part-time software developer for HairbowCenter and am helping out with another company called Sekan Printing and Occasion Shops. Most efficient when working and collaborating with others. Avid lifetime learner and passionate about automation of repetitive tasks, providing meaningful solutions to businesses, and exceptional visual design.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Kansas State University**

Manhattan, KS

Full Stack Software Development Professional Certificate

July 2022

**Courses:** Front-End Development, UI-UX, Back-End Development and APIs, React-Redux, SQL and Data Modeling, MERN-stack Project, Principles of Programming in Python, Advanced Programming Topics

#### **SKILLS PROFILE**

**Certification:** Software Engineer

**Development Technologies:** JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Flask, CSS, SASS, SCSS, HTML, AWS, VS Code, Visual Studio, GitHub, PgAdmin, C#, .NET, PSQL, Sequelize, Postman, Trello, APIs, Jinja, Git, React, Redux, NodeJS,

Express, Bootstrap, Mongoose, Axios, macOS, Linux, Windows, AWS4

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

**Deployment Tools:** GitHub Pages, Heroku, Netlify, ElephantSQL, MongoDB Atlas, Amazon S3 Bucket, AWS Elastic

Beanstalk, CircleCI, Microsoft Azure Web App

### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

MERNstagram May 2022

- Engineered a full scale PERN-stack application in collaboration with three other classmates at K-State for a group milestone project.
- Create, view, edit, and delete social media posts in this application like you would with similar social media apps.
- App is hosted in three places: the client is hosted on Netlify, the server is hosted on Heroku, and the Database is hosted with ElephantSQL.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Material-UI, PostgreSQL, React, Git, ElephantSQL, PgAdmin, Axios, Express, NodeJS, and JSX.
- This project was instrumental in showing all of the group how to function as a team, develop in a real-world development environment, and properly use all of the different version control features of git and github.

REST-Rant March 2022

- Engineered a full-stack application that allows users to review restaurants while admin roles have privileges to add restaurants, remove users, and remove reviews.
- Implemented user authentication with roles.
- The app is hosted on Heroku and uses MongoDB as a database.

 Development technologies include JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, JSX, and express-react-views.

Music API April 2022

- Developed a JavaScript Backend API for a full-fledged music tour as a part of the course at K-State.
- Users can send requests, use all CRUD operations, and view responses rendered as JSON in the browser or in the terminal.
- Project demonstrates a large relational SQL database with many tables.
- API uses PostgreSQL as a database and implements Sequelize as an object document mapping solution.

# Pokemon\_Battle\_Game

January 2022–February 2022

- Developed a fully-functional Pokémon battle game that runs in the browser using raw HTML, CSS, and JavaScript as a solo milestone project for K-State.
- The JavaScript logic allows for a user to choose his or her party of Pokémon and then battle against a computer player and its Pokémon until the user wins or loses.
- Project consists of large amounts of JavaScript logic, HTML objects, CSS styling, and sprites.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

August 2022–Present

Software Developer

- Develop task automation web applications
- Write Jinja templates in ERP system
- Create data collection web applications
- Continue with previous responsibilities

# Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

February 2020-August 2022

Catalog Listing Assistant

- List highly detailed and niche products on Amazon, Etsy, Walmart
- Communicate regularly with the product analyst and the sales department in creating the varying products with details that are oriented for sales optimization
- Fix broken listings and update prices to increase profit margins

## Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

April 2014–February 2020

Warehouse Laborer

- Worked in product production and conversion
- Converted large product units to multiple smaller product units while operating a machine
- Kept shelves saturated with products for pickers
- Troubleshoot inventory errors using an online SKU-based inventory management system and communication with co-workers